Finding Aid for the Lester Breslow Papers LSC.2246
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lester Breslow papers
1932-2009
UCLA Library Special Collections
Breslow, Lester, 1915-2012
LSC.2246
53.6 Linear Feet (134 boxes)
Lester Breslow was a former dean of the UCLA School of Public Health, professor emeritus of health services, and one of the leading figures in public health. He was born March 17, 1915 in Bismarck, ND, and received a BS in Psychology (1935) from the University of Minnesota, where he also earned his medical and public health degrees (MD, 1938; MPH, 1941). He is widely known for his early advocacy and research into health promotion and disease prevention. This collection consists of materials related to Breslow's professional research, scholarship, and leadership in the field of public health both as a UCLA professor and as a researcher and advocate in non-UCLA affiliated projects. The papers include professional correspondence, research notes and files, authored reports and related materials, conference presentation and talks, legislative testimonies and related materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: This collection contains processed digital materials. Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Source of Acquisition
Devra Breslow; Gift; 2014.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9985825133606533
Biographical / Historical
Lester Breslow was a former dean of the UCLA School of Public Health, professor emeritus of health services, and one of the leading figures in public health. He was born March 17, 1915 in Bismarck, ND, and received a BS in Psychology (1935) from the University of Minnesota, where he also earned his medical and public health degrees (MD, 1938; MPH, 1941).
After serving as a US Army captain in the Pacific Division during World War II, Breslow went on to the California Department of Public Health, first as Chief of the Bureau of Chronic Diseases (1946-1960), then Chief of the Division of Preventive Medical Services (1960-1965), and then Director of Public Health (1965-1968). Breslow is widely known for his early advocacy and research into health promotion and disease prevention. Through pioneering studies relying on the Alameda County Human Population Laboratory beginning in the early 1960s, he helped to identify the important influence of behavior on disability and premature death. His research was among the first to show that simple health practices, such as getting regular exercise and sleep, not drinking excessively, not smoking, and maintaining a healthy weight, supports longer and better quality of life.
Breslow joined the UCLA School of Public Health faculty in 1968, serving as Dean of the School of Public Health from 1972-1980, and continued speaking and writing as professor emeritus well into his 90s. He served on numerous local, state, national, and international associations and commissions. He served as president of the International Epidemiological Association (1967-1968), the American Public Health Association (1968-1969), and the American Schools of Public Health (1973-1975). Breslow passed away in Los Angeles on April 9, 2012.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials related to the professional research, scholarship, and leadership in the field of public health of American physician Lester Breslow, a UCLA professor and dean of the School of Public Health. His research interests were health promotion, disease prevention, and public health programs. The papers include professional correspondence, research notes and files, authored reports and related materials, conference presentations and talks, legislative testimonies and related materials. This collection also includes administrative materials such as correspondence, memos, agendas, and reports related to Breslow's work at the UCLA School of Public health, as well as his extensive involvement with local, state, and national committees and commissions.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Teaching and university affairs, 1938-2009
Series 2: Research scholarship, 1932-2008
Subseries 2.1: Resource files, 1932-2005
Subseries 2.2: Grants and research, 1958-2006
Subseries 2.3: Publications and reports, 1949-2008
Subseries 2.4: Conference presentations and talks, 1955-2007
Series 3: Non-university work, 1950-2009
Subseries 3.1: Committees and consulting, 1971-2009
Subseries 3.2: Legislation and testimonies, 1950-2003
Materials are organized alphabetically, with the exception Subseries 2.3. Materials in Subseries 2.3 are organized chronologically.
Public health -- United States; Health care reform -- United States; Health promotion -- United States; Breslow, Lester, 1915-2012 -- Archives; University of California, Los Angeles. School of Public Health. Faculty -- Archives
- Series 1: Teaching and university affairs, 1938-2009
  Scope and Contents
  This series is composed of professional correspondence and materials related to Breslow's occupation as faculty member and dean of the UCLA School of Public Health (SPH), including biographical materials, administrative and planning documents, memos, and reports. The correspondence is largely between Breslow and colleagues at UCLA, other universities, and local and national agencies. Breslow was involved in the establishment of public health education programs throughout the UC system, as well as evaluation and development of UC employee health advocacy and medical plans.
  - Biographical materials, 1968-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Abrams, Herbet, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Affifi, Abdelmonem, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Armed Forces Epidemiological Board, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Bernstein, James, National Health Network, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Cook, Donald, 1983 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Fielding, Jonathan, 1976-2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Finucane, Mark, Los Angeles County Department of Health Services (LACDHS), 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Glantz, Stanton, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Lester Gorsline Associates, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Halfon, Neal, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Louis Harris and Associates, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Health Services and Mental Health Administration, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Healthfax, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Karnow, Marvin, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Karsh, Yousuf, 1980 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Kitching, William, 1974 August 15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Los Angeles County Medical Advisory Council, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Los Angeles Office of Mayor, 1973-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: The Nation's Health, 1975 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Preventive medical services in state funded medical care programs, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Public Citizen's Health Research Group, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Riedel, Donald, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Rivin, Arthur, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Russo, Anthony, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Satellite Network of America, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Udvarhelvyi, George B., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: White, Gates, and Fielding, 1980 October (Box 2, Folder 18, Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Viseltear/Carter, 1975-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Zeko, Thomas, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 7-9, Box 4, Folder 2-7)
  - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 7-8, Box 5, Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 8-9, Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 6, Folder 4-7)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - UCLA: Academic Program Planning Review Board, UC Health Sciences Committee, 1975-1985 (Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11)
  - UCLA: Academic Senate, 1981-1984 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - UCLA: Ad Hoc Committee on Psychological and Psychiatric Services, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
  - UCLA: Ad Hoc Committee, Harary, 1982 March 24 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - UCLA: California Council for Health Plan Alternatives, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - UCLA: Center for Adolescent Health Promotion, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 7, Box 13, Folder 1)
  - UCLA: Center on Aging, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - UCLA: Center for Health Enhancement Education and Policy, circa 1981-1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - UCLA: Center for Health Policy Research, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - UCLA: Chancellor's Public Service Committee, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - UCLA: Child Health Care Pre-Payment Plan, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - UCLA: Clinical Cancer Prevention Elective, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - UCLA: Committee on Alcohol and Drug Abuse, 1972-1975 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - UCLA: Committee for the Center for the Study and Reduction of Violence, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 7-10, Box 14, Box 15, Folder 1)
  - UCLA: Committee on Delivery of Services to Defined Populations, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - UCLA: Dental Research Institute, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - UCLA: Dentistry, School of, 1982-1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - UCLA: Dependency disorders, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - UCLA: Distinguished lectureship, 1980-1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - UCLA: Division of Health Services meeting minutes, 1983-1987 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - UCLA: General, 1985-1986 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - UCLA: Gerontology Center, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - UCLA: Graduate Council, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - UCLA: Health Promotion Center, 1982-1986 (Box 16, Folder 5-7)
  - UCLA: Institute of Government and Public Affairs, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - UCLA: Medicine, School of, 1972-1986 (Box 16, Folder 9-10, Box 17, Folder 1)
  - UCLA: National Health Law Program, 1976-1981 (Box 17, Folder 2-5)
  - UCLA: Neuropsychiatric Institute, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - UCLA: Nursing, School of, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - UCLA: Program for Advanced Study of Social and Behavioral Sciences, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - UCLA SPH: Administrative materials, circa 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 9, Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - UCLA SPH: Annual reports, 1980-1988 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - UCLA SPH: Association of Schools of Public Health, 1978-1980 (Box 18, Folder 5-8)
  - UCLA SPH: Beverly Myers faculty appointment, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - UCLA SPH: Bioterrorism, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - UCLA SPH: California Pipe Trade Council, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - UCLA SPH: China Exchange, 1982-1992 (Box 19, Folder 4-9, Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - UCLA SPH: Community Affairs Committee, 1981-1986 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - UCLA SPH: Community involvement, 1982-1999 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - UCLA SPH: Community health report card, 1997-1999 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - UCLA SPH: Dean's Advisory Board, 1995-2007 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
  - UCLA SPH: Drew University collaboration, 1984-1998 (Box 20, Folder 9-11)
  - UCLA SPH: Evaluations of administrators and staff, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - UCLA SPH: Faculty interviews, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - UCLA SPH: Faculty-student ratio, 1976 March 9 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - UCLA SPH: Goals and objectives, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - UCLA SPH: Health Behavior and Cancer Control Advisory Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - UCLA SPH: Health Impact Assessment Impact Project, 2002-2003 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - UCLA SPH: Health Services, Department of, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - UCLA SPH: Hospital Satellite Network, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - UCLA SPH: HS 207 guest lecture, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - UCLA SPH: Jonsson Cancer Center, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - UCLA SPH: Los Angeles County Department of Health Services, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - UCLA SPH: Merger of Department of Preventive Medicine and Social Medicine and School of Public Health, 1972-1975 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - UCLA SPH: Office of Smoking and Health, 1978-1981 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - UCLA SPH: Preventive Medicine Residency program, 1981-1987 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - UCLA SPF: Professional schools restructuring initiatives, 1993-1996 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - UCLA SPF: Publications, 1968-1987 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - UCLA SPF: Statements by Breslow as Dean of SPH, 1973-1976 (Box 22, Folder 3-15)
  - UCLA SPF: Strategic Planning Community Committee, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - UCLA SPH: Student Affairs Committee, 1981-1985 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - UC: Health Assessment/Living Well, 2005-2006 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - UC: Health plans, 2002-2006 (Box 23, Folder 4-6)
  - UC: Stay Well/Wellness Coalition, 1993-2007 (Box 23, Folder 7-8, Box 24, Folder 1-5)
- Series 2: Research and scholarship, 1932-2008
  This series consists of materials related to the research and scholarship conducted by Breslow. His research interests were health promotion, disease prevention, and public health programs. Materials include correspondence, research notes and files, authored reports and related materials, conference presentations and talks.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Subseries 2.1: Resource files, 1932-2005
    This subseries consists of Breslow's subject files related to his research, as well as materials related to his personal life. This includes correspondence, data sets, reports, meeting minutes and agendas, materials related to the Academic Senate, faculty interviews, and lectures. Topics include AIDS, air pollution, health care issues in California, cancer, public health legislation, pre-paid health plans, anti-smoking campaigns, correspondence with public health administrator David Satcher, and tobacco.
    - AIDS, 1988-1989 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Air pollution, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Assorted, 1981-2004 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin of the International Corresponding Club, 1955-1958 (Box 25, Folder 2-4)
    - Bureau of Health Care Services, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - CA health issues, 1953-1980 (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
    - California legislation: Beilenson legislation, 1973-1975 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - California policy seminar, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Cancer control and research methods, 1963-1977 (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
    - Cardiovascular data, 1974-1975 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Carter, Jimmy file, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Center for Health Enhancement Education and Research, 1980-1985 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Coastal region public health service, 1981-1984 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - E.I. Dupont de Nemours and Co., 1979-1984 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
    - Evaluation criteria for functioning pre-paid health plans and HMOs, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
    - Governor's health care proposal, circa 2007 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Group Against Smoking Pollution (GASP), 1970 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Health care, 1970-1980 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Health consequences of the Casmalia resources waste disposal facility, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Health promotion, 1940-1991 (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
    - Health publications, circa 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Health workers, 1975-1976 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Heart disease, 1978 October (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Implications of national health insurance for health care in California, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Incorporation of preventive medical services into national health services, circa 1974-1978 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Kabasele, Karl. Transcripts of oral interviews, 1997 September (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
    - Mammography, 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - National Cancer Institute, 1974-1978 (Box 29, Folder 2-4)
    - National health insurance, 1932-1977 (Box 29, Folder 5-7)
    - Pediatrics, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Preventive health care, 1967-1994 (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
    - Progress report on mammography, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Responses to "Challenges" listed in community-based cancer program, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - San Diego State University, circa 1981 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Santa Barbara County health care service, 1980-1982 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Satcher, David, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Smoking and medical care, 1960-1977, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - State of California, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Tobacco: Enstrom, James, circa 2000-2005 (Box 30, Folder 6, Box 31, Folder 1)
    - US health care reform and public health, 1993 April (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Veterans administration, 1982-1986 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Violence prevention programs, circa 1991-1994 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Vitamin A material, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Weinerman, E.R., 1970 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Well-being and medical care, 1973-1980 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Western consortium, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2.2: Grants and research, 1958-2006
    This subseries contains materials related to grants and funding for Breslow's research projects. This includes correspondence, reports, applications, meeting minutes, and planning and program documents. Areas of research or funders include the American Cancer Society's California division, public health improvement projects, children's health care, the Kaiser Family Foundation, community cancer control in Los Angeles, Medi-Cal programs, national health insurance, cancer and related health risks, and the Human Population Laboratory (HPL). HPL was a landmark study conducted in Alameda County by Breslow which looked at the correlation between lifestyle factors such as exercise, smoking, and sleep and a person's lifespan.
    SUBSERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - American Cancer Society-California division, 1971-1973 (Box 31, Folder 9-11)
    - American Health Foundation, 1971-1977 (Box 31, Folder 12-13, Box 32, Folder 1-5)
    - Beverly Hills school district, circa 1983-1984 (Box 32, Folder 6-9, Box 33, Box 34, Folder 1-7)
    - California Council for Health Plan Alternatives, 1968-1971 (Box 34, Folder 8, Box 35, Box 36)
    - California public health improvement project, 1982-1998 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - California state health plan policy strategy, 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 2-4)
    - Center for Ischemic Cardiovascular Disease, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Children's coverage program, 2005 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Children health services, 2001-2005 (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
    - Community cancer control, Los Angeles, 1976-1984 (Folder 38, Box 39, Box 40, Box 41, Folder 1)
    - El Monte health promotion, 1989-1994 (Box 41, Folder 2-7, Box 42, Folder 1-3)
    - Enstrom, epidemiology of cancer among Mormons, 1975-1980 (Box 42, Folder 4-7, Box 43)
    - Health care financing administration, 1996-2000 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
    - Health risk appraisal for the elderly, 1997-1998 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Health promotion, 1982-1992 (Box 44, Folder 4-6)
    - Health maintenance committee, 1980-1981 (Box 44, Folder 7-8)
    - Healthy children, circa 1985 (Box 44, Folder 9, Box 45, Folder 1)
    - History of cancer control, 1974-1977 (Box 45, Folder 2-8, Box 46, Box 47, Box 48, Folder 1)
    - HIV prevention trials unit, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Human population laboratory, 1958-2001 (Box 48, Folder 3-7, Box 49, Box 50, Box 51, Box 52, Folder 1-3)
      Box 48 contains one CD labelled: HPL - Breslow data.
      BOX 48 CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - Kaiser Family Foundation health promotion program, 1986-1989 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Know Your Body program, circa 1995 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Los Angeles cancer control research unit, 1975-1985 (Box 52, Folder 6-7, Box 53, Box 54, Box 55, Box 56, Folder 1-2)
    - Mammography, 1975-1978 (Box 56, Folder 3-6, Box 57, Box 58, Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Medi-Cal, 1966-1975 (Box 59, Folder 2-7, Box 60, Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1977-1982 (Box 61, Folder 2-4)
    - National Coalition on Disease Prevention and Environmental Health, 1978-1979 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - National health insurance committee, 1970-1980 (Box 61, Folder 6-7, Box 62, Box 63, Box 64, Box 65, Box 66, Box 67, Box 68, Box 69, Box 70, Folder 1-4)
    - Natural history of health disparities, 2001-2004 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - New York Academy of Sciences public health and medicine, 1996-1997 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Prevention of disease, 1977-1978 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Proposition 99, 1989-1995 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Public health programs for California children, circa 2004-2006 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Rand Corporation, 1973-1983 (Box 71, Folder 4-6)
    - Risk factors project, 1978-1984 (Box 71, Folder 7-13, Box 72, Box 73, Box 74, Box 75, Box 76, Box 77, Box 78, Box 79, Box 80, Box 81)
    - School health, undated (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Senior health profile, 1994-1997 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Task force on heart disease, 1978 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - UCLA cancer control developmental outreach grant, 1974-1984 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - UCLA Jonsson Cancer Center Core Grant, 1980-1982 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2.3: Publications and reports, 1949-2008
    This subseries covers reports and other publications authored or co-authored by Breslow. Materials include correspondence, notes, and reports. Topics addressed in this subseries include cancer and health care, epidemiology, health education, mammography, follow-up for the San Mateo nutrition study, and links between smoking, chronic diseases and cancer.
    - Cancer and healthcare, 1960-1968 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Epidemiology manpower, circa 1974 (Box 82, Folder 7-8)
    - Health education and promotion, 1966-2003 (Box 82, Folder 9, Box 83, Folder 1-5)
    - Lifetime health monitoring program, 1968-1978 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Malignant melanoma for Kaiser Foundation, 1984-1985 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Mammography, 1977 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Measuring health in the third era, 2007-2008 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Policies for cancer control, circa 1988-1991 (Box 84, Folder 1-2)
    - Risk factors, 1977-1979 (Box 84, Folder 3-4)
    - Seven-year follow-up of the San Mateo nutrition study population, 1957 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Smoking, chronic disease, and cancer, 1949-1958 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2.4: Conference presentations and talks, 1955-2007 (Box 84, Folder 7-18, Box 85, Box 86, Box 87, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 91, Box 92, Box 93, Box 94, Box 95, Box 96, Folder 1-5)
    This subseries contains materials related to conferences Breslow attended and talks he gave. Topics include children's health care, health care provision in California, environmentally influenced disease, the role of health workers, epidemiology, the Human Population Laboratory, and the National Conference on Preventative Medicine. Box 94 includes one DVD that contains a lecture by Breslow.
    Arrangement